Sophie Berger

BSc in Computer Science and Masters of Management student at UBC Android, iOS, Web and AR experience Microsoft Imagine cup Regional Finalist, and Hackathon winner

+1 (236) 862-3848 berger.m.sophie@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sophiemb github.com/SophieMBerger sophiemberger.github.io/

"Strength Insight Report" (from Gallup / CliftonStrengths): Achiever, Strategic, Learner, Futuristic, Focus

Skills

Proficient: Java (6 yrs), Swift (3 yrs), Firebase, ARKit Familiar: C, C++, Kotlin, Python, JavaScript, React, Unity, Tensorflow, HTML, CSS

Experience

Undergraduate Researcher

03/2020 - 08/2020

USRA/SURE internship through UBC

- AR-based instructions for elderly users
- Supervised by Prof. Dongwook Yoon

Equity-owner of "Mindset" startup 10/2019 – Present

iOS Front-end developer/equity-owner

- Front-end development on dementia screening iOS app using Swift
- Analyzed iOS UI/UX compatibility
- Wrote a tech-specification document for outsourced development

Tailored Apps

05/2019 - 07/2019

iOS Software Developer Intern

- Implemented Firebase authentication/Cloud **Functions**
- Added AR and object recognition using ARKit
- Parsed Json from a database for in-app deep links
- <u>Serialized data</u> using the Codable protocol
- Localized using a Fastlane Google-Sheet plugin
- Helped CTO estimate the feasibility/pricing of a Machine Learning project

Competitions

Microsoft Imagine Cup Regional Finalist

05/2019

Americas regional final

(bit.ly/imaginenekotap)

- In top 12 teams out 30,000+ participants in the Americas
- Presented at the Microsoft Build conference
- Same as "nekoTap" project below

1st place at nwHacks with "nekoTap"

01/2019

Western Canada's largest Hackathon (1000+ participants)

(devpost.com/software/nekotap)

- Android app for improved drug adherence using NFC technology to receive tailored drug information
- Designed animations using Lottie library and implemented Android front-end using Java to increase usability/accessibility within the app

Education

BSc in Computer Science

09/2018 - 12/2022

+ Master of Management:

09/ 2018 - 12/ 2023

- Average = 83.9%, Dean's honor list
- Relevant courses: Models of computation, Software construction, Introduction to Computer Systems, Basic Algorithms and Data Structures

"Java Foundations Certified Junior

03/2017

Associate" - Awarded by Oracle University

Selected projects

Soil TopARgraphy

10/ 2018 - Present

Android & Unity Developer for UBC Launchpad (eml.ubc.ca/projects/soil-topargraphy/)

- <u>Created</u> an **AR** app for Dr. Maja Krzic's soil science class at UBC
- Created Android front-end using Kotlin and Java
- Added UI features to custom AR map in Unity
- Offers more engaging education to 250+ students
- <u>Utilized</u> Google Maps Android SDK for location
- <u>Presented</u> at UBC "Multidisciplinary Undergraduate Research Conference"

Google NIMA in TensorFlow Lite

07/2019

Proof of concept for TailoredApps

(bit.ly/TFLiteGoogleNIMA)

- Converted existing "Neural Image Assessment" models to TensorFlow Lite models using Python
- Developed an iOS project to rank images and determine the "best" overall image using Swift

Community Involvement

Microsoft Student Partner (MSP)

09/2019 - Present

Microsoft

Represented Microsoft and educated about technology on social media/my university campus